[music]
Cool, so now when we
press play our spawn manager
spawns one of our
obstacles, but we do need
to spawn more obstacles so
that way it's more like a game.
So in our spawn manager script,
we're going to set it
so that we can actually
create all of these
obstacles at intervals again.
So first what we're going to do is we're
going to create another custom script
so that we can spawn these obstacles.
So we'll call this void spawn obstacle.
Make sure you put parentheses,
enter, create those curly brackets,
and then we already
have a line of code to
create a new obstacle.
So we're just going to
take this entire line and we're going to
cut it and paste it into spawn obstacle.
Now we're going to reuse that method that
we used before called invoke repeating.
That's not in the
right place at all.
That's better. So invoke
repeating, we'll use to
constantly call our spawn
obstacle method over time.
So we're going to use
the name of our method,
which is spawn obstacle.
And we're going to
give it a time to start
at. So in this case,
we'll just call this start delay so that
we give our player a little bit of time.
And then we're going
to give it a rate that it's
going to constantly
repeat at. So we'll just
call this repeat rate.
And then our computers
matter to us because we
actually haven't created
those variables. So
we'll do a private float
for the start delay since we know that
two is generally a good number to start at.
So don't really need to
change that one around.
And then for the repeat
rate, we'll just change
this in code if we need
to. So private float,
repeat rate, and we'll
just have repeat every
two seconds as well.
Now if I go back into Unity,
you can see that eventually we have these
obstacles that spawn and they fly very fast.
Probably change that later.
And then there are player goes.
Now one thing that
you might notice
aside from all the
obstacles that are just flying
away in the distance
is that at some point,
our player starts to lean over
and that looks kind of weird.
A really cool thing that you can do, especially
with rigid bodies is you can see under
all of these different options for our
rigid body, there's actually constraints.
So if I actually open up
constraints, we don't actually want
our player to be able to
turn or move in any other
direction except the Y.
So we're actually going
to just freeze the
position of the X and the Z,
as well as freeze the
rotation of the X and the Z.
And really we actually
didn't want the player
to go up and down. So
that's just the Y position.
So we'll just freeze
the rotation of the Y too.
So now whenever the player gets hit by
an obstacle, they won't turn side to side.
They'll just constantly only
be able to move up or down.
So if we press play. And
then if I try and avoid these
obstacles as best as I can,
and I just jumped over that one.
And so then let's see what
happens if we run into one.
Cool. And just get
hit by the obstacle.
Nothing happens other than
that. I don't get these weird
tilts that happen
or anything like that.
So perfect. That's exactly
what we're looking for.
So now what you're going
to do is create your own
variables inside spawn
manager for the start delay
and the repeat rate.
You're going to take your
instantiate method from
start. And you're going to
create a new custom
method called spawn obstacle.
So then that way you can
just call spawn obstacle
whenever you need to
create a new obstacle.
And then we're going to
reuse that invoke repeating
method that we had before
so that we can constantly
call spawn obstacle.
And it won't start until
two seconds and then
it will repeat every two
seconds afterwards.
And then last but not least,
you're going to use
rigid body constraints to
actually freeze everything
except the Y position.
So that way the player
can only move up or
down whenever they
jump. Now it's your turn.
(dramatic music)